A Finding Aid to the William P. Daley Papers, 1905-2016 (bulk 1951-2001), in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Workshops, Seminars, and Lectures, 1958-1998, undated; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 2.3 Linear feet Boxes 6-8
  - Massachusetts College of Art, 1991, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Portland School of Art, 1991, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - NEA Visual Artist Fellowships/ Crafts Panel, 1991-1992; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - NCECA 1992, 1991-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 5-6)
  - "American Crafts: The Nation's Collection" Symposium, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Foundations in Art Theory and Education Conference, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Southeastern Massachusetts University, circa 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Wayne Art Center, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - 92nd Street Y "Artists Visions" Series, 1992-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - "World Turning Conference", 1992-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - North County Studio Conference, 1992-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - NCECA 1993, 1993, Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Jarrettown Elementary School, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - The Craft Experience in Art Education, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - "Central Bucks High School East Art Day", 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Wood Turning Center "Challenge V", 1993-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Penland School of Crafts, 1993-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 19-20)
  - Oregon School of Arts and Crafts, 1993-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Harding Black Dinner, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - State University of New York, New Paltz, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - University of Northern Iowa, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Corcoran School of Art, 1994, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Cornell University, 1994, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Art Education Association of Indiana Annual Conference, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - The Craft Experience in Art Education II, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Michigan Potters' Association, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Conestoga and Great Valley High Schools, 1994, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Philadelphia College of Art and Design Summer MFA Program, 1994-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Anderson Ranch Arts Center, 1994-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - 25th Annual Glass Art Society Conference, 1994-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 33-34)
  - The Craft Experience in Art Education III, 1994-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Potters Guild of Baltimore, 1994-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Penncrest High School, 1994-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Pewabic Pottery Exhibit and Workshop, 1994-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - University of Oregon, 1994-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Westminster Presbyterian Church, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - "Fletcher Challenge Ceramic Award", 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Manchester Craftsmen's Guild, 1995, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - William Penn Charter School, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Cheltenham High School, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Penland School of Crafts, 1995-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Towson State University, 1995-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - "Teaching the Arts: A Dialogue Between Art Educators", 1995-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - "1997 World Turning Conference", 1995-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - 1996 ACC Craft Fair: Baltimore, Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Penn Charter Gallery Talk, circa 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Community College of Philadelphia, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - NCECA '96, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Voorhees High School, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - New Hope-Solebury High School, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Abington Friends School, circa 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Princeton University, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Interlocutor's Talk, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Pennsylvania Art Education Association Conference, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - NCECA '98, 1997-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Cheltenham Center for the Arts, 1997-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Northern Clay Center, 1998, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - Appalachian Center for Crafts, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Souderton High School, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 63)
- Writings, 1951-2003, undated; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 0.6 Linear feet Box 9
  This series houses writings by William Daley and others as well as Daley's personal address lists and calendars. Writings by Daley contain articles, speeches, and other writings. These include artist reviews, autobiographical essays, essays on art, and essays on education. Many files provide several drafts and edited versions with handwritten notations. Also found within the files are related materials including correspondence and clippings of published versions of the artist's writings. Writings by Others contain two articles and one lecture on the art of William Daily, as well as essays on other art topics. Also included are a thesis proposal on ceramics and a master's thesis on the University of the Arts Foundation Program.
  Writings are arranged into three subseries:
  6.1: Writings by Daley, 1951-1999, undated
  6.2: Writings by Others, 1980-2003, undated
  6.3: Address Lists and Calendars, 1968-2000, undated
  - Writings by Daley, 1951-1999, undated; 6.1; Archival Resource Key
    - Articles, "Artist & Teacher," School Arts, 1962-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Articles, "Helen Drutt Gallery," Gold Smiths Journal, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Articles, "Celebration of Clay," American Craft, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Articles, NCECA Journal Article, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Articles, "On Drawing", circa 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Articles, "Recollections From Old Notes and Canted Memories," American Clay Artists, 1988-1992, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Articles, American Craft Magazine, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Articles, NCECA Conference Newsletter, circa 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Speeches, Cosmopolitan Club/Trenton Community College, circa 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Speeches, "Aspects of the Apollonian Ideal", 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Speeches, William Daley: 1990-1980 Gallery Talk, circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Speeches, Notes for NASCAD Graduation Talk, circa 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Speeches, "Inside/Outside", 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Other, "The Social Function of Art", 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Other, "Wayne Higby", 1978-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Other, Pfannebecker Collection Review, circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Other, "A Form Maker's Perception on 'The Case for Clay in Secondary Education'", 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Other, "John Glick", 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Other, Miscellaneous, 1999, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Writings by Others, 1980-2003, undated; 6.2; Archival Resource Key
    - Chambers, Karen S., "A Daley Quest: Seeking the Essence of Clay," The World & I, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Church, Sharon, "Gothic Affinities", 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Fraenkel, Richard, Lecture, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Jepsen, David A., "The Language of Career Development", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Kokis, George, "The Translucent Object", 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - McTwigan, Michael, "William Daley: In Search of the Vessel," American Craft, 1980-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Rapone, Joseph, "The Foundation Program at the University of the Arts: History Methodology, and Ideology," Masters Thesis, 2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Rattner, Carl, Proposal for "Ranges of meaning in selected contemporary ceramic sculpture manifesting hard and soft form characteristics", 1986-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Address Lists and Calendars, 1968-2000, undated; 6.3; Archival Resource Key
    - Address Lists, 1968, 1994-2000, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 28-29)
    - Calendars, 1989-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 30-36)
- Teaching Files, 1951-1998, undated; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 1.3 Linear feet Boxes 9-10
  This series contains materials relating to Daley's career as an art professor, primarily at the Philadelphia College of Art from 1965 to 1990. Files on his early career contain correspondence, records, and evaluations. Files pertaining to the Philadelphia College of Art include curriculums, lesson notes, and assignments for several courses. Also found are department mission statements and semester grades. Much of the material was either written by Daley himself or with his colleagues. At the end of the series are several files of general teaching materials, including more notes on ceramics, kiln instructions, and teaching contracts. Items of note in this series are Daley's dismantled ceramics notebook and "Ceramic Shop Notes," as well as materials on a course entitled Concept Development which include many original hand drawn diagrams and illustrations. Files are arranged chronologically by academic institution with general materials arranged chronologically at the end of the series.
  - Alfred University, Ceramics Notebook, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Iowa State Teachers College, 1951-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - State University of New York, State Teachers College, 1954-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - University of New Mexico, Guest Professor, 1971-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Appointment to Faculty, 1969-1972, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Changes to the Campus, 1966, 1974, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Industrial Design Department, 1972-1976, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Craft Department Mission and Goal Statements, 1986, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Foundation Program Curriculum, 1965-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, "Foundation Course Information", 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Foundation Program Assignments and Lesson Notes, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Concept Development Curriculum and Diagrams, 1971-1991, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 48-50)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Dismantled Concept Development Notebook, 1976-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Sophomore Assignments and Lecture Notes, 1983, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Junior Ceramics Assignments, 1970-1988, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Dismantled Junior Ceramics Assignment Notebook, 1980-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Ceramics Senior Projects, 1981-1989, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Proposed Senior Project and Craft Curriculum, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Ceramic Studio Residence Program, 1989, 1995, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Craft Department Self Study, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Philadelphia College of Art, Semester Grades, 1973-1990, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 8-10)
  - General Notes on Teaching Art and Ceramics, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence About Teaching Positions, 1956, 1963-1978, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Teaching Contracts, 1961-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Dismantled Ceramics Notebook, circa 1968-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 14-22)
  - "Ceramic Shop Notes", 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 23-24)
  - Kiln Instructions, 1980, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous, 1988-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 26)
- Artist Files, 1938-2001, undated; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 2.1 Linear feet Boxes 10-12
  This series contains files for artists who were colleagues or friends of William Daley, and may include announcements and invitations to the artist's exhibitions, correspondence with Daley, biographical material such as resumes, printed material, and photographs of the artist. Correspondence between Daley and the artists include incoming letters, postcards, and drafts of outgoing letters. Many of the artists were either Daley's students or co-workers, and most of the files contain material spanning ten years or more. Also found is a transcribed interview William Daley conducted of artist Viktor Schrekengost in 1996. Materials in this series are arranged alphabetical by artist's last name.
  - Andrade, Edna, 1983, 1993-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Arneson, Robert, 1979-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Autio, Rudy, 1980-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Bae, Jin Hwan, 1990, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Black, Harding, 1990-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Bodine, Sarah and Michael Dunas, 1987, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Bonner, Jonathan, 1989-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Bonovitz, Jill, 1989-1998, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Boughner, Cynthia, 1994-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Brady, Robert, 1981-1995, Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Bouillard, William, 1990, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Bunker, George, 1965, 1986-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Carreiro, Joseph, 1957, 1978, 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Chappelle, Robert, 1985-1996, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 9-10)
  - Chihuly, Dale, 1978-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 11-12)
  - Cho, Chung Hyun, 1989-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Church, Sharon, 1990, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Colker, Ed, 1985-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Cushing, Val, 1970-1984, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Dailey, Dan, 1978-1998, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 17-18)
  - DeVore, Richard, 1975-1997, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Doran, Patricia, 1990-1996, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Duckworth, Ruth, 1977-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Duryea, Lynn, 1990-1998, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Eberle, Edward, 1978-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Erlebacher, Walter, 1991-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Ferguson, Ken, 1981-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Flexer, Mindy, 1986, 1992, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Frey, Viola, 1981-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Gill, John, 1982-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Glick, John, 1979-1997, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Goodman, Sidney, 1975-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Greenamyer, George, 1980-1998, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Harvey, Rebecca, 1993-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Hepburn, Tony, 1980-1991, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Higby, Wayne, 1973-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Holzapfel, Michelle, 1991-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Howard, Robert, 1981-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 36-37)
  - Hsu, Chia-sueih, 1988-1997, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Jaffe, Jeanne, 1989, 1995-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Karros, Alec, 1983-2001, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Kuo, Yih-Wen, 1990-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Levine, Marilyn, 1979-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Marks, Graham, 1977-1995, undated, Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 5-6)
  - Martin, Stephen, 1984, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Mayo, Noel, 1993, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Metzker, Ray, 1981-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Naples, Lisa, 1986-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Neff, Edith, 1979-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Ottenberg, Perry, 1982, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Owens-Hart, Winnie, 1979, 1987-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Pewabic Pottery, 1986-1989, 1993, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Piper, Jane, 1976-1990, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Reinhardt, Richard, 1969, 1974, 1984-1999, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Roehm, Mary, 1987, 1994-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Salomon, Judith, 1988, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Schreckengost, Viktor, 1979-1997, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 19-20)
  - Seelig, Warren, 1983-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Shin, Sang-ho, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Simoncelli, Chris, 1985, 1990-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Staffel, Rudolf, 1966-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Staley, Chris, 1982-1993, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Stephenson, John and Susanne, 1978-2001, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 26-27)
  - Stewart, Lizbeth, 1979-1991, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Takaezu, Toshiko, 1990-1998, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Troy, Jack, 1983-1998, undated; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 30-31)
  - Turner, Robert, 1979-1996, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Vaskys, Petras, 1984, 1986, 1997, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Vavrek, Ken, 1982-1994, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Voulkos, Peter, 1952, 1976-1993, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Winokur, Paula and Robert, 1976-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Woell, J. Fred, 1994-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Woodman, Betty, 1977-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Wright, David, 1989-1998, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Wyman, William, 1978-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Zaeder, Thayer, 1986-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Zeisel, Eva, 1992, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Miscellaneous, A-M, 1985-2000, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Miscellaneous, N-Z, 1938, 1984-1994, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 44)
- Reference Files, 1951-2001, undated; Series 9; Archival Resource Key; 1 Linear foot Box 13; (Box 13; 1.0 linear foot)
  This series contains material on a variety of topics that William Daley compiled as reference files for projects and teaching. This includes files on the art of various countries, in the form of postcards, maps, and guidebooks, as well as files of numerous published or handwritten formulas, tables, and directions for using ceramic or other sculptural materials. Also found are materials on art, craft, and education, and other general subjects in the form of photocopies or clippings of articles. These files also include teaching materials written and originally used by others. This series is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Africa, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Animals and Nature, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Architecture, 1984, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 3-4)
  - Art Censorship, 1990-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Art Education, 1953, 1983-1998, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 6-8)
  - Art Essays, 1973-1994, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 9-10)
  - The Brain, 1995-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Ceramic History, 1988-1992, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 12-13)
  - Ceramics Technical Notebook, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Ceramic Toxicology, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - China, 1980, 1990, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 16-17)
  - Clay Bodies and Mixing Slips, 1968-1980, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 18-19)
  - Clay Materials: Technical Analysis, 1967-1977, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Craft Philosophy, 1967, 1986-2001, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Earthenware, 1977, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Ecology, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Education, 1995, 2000, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - England, circa 1986, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - France, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Frank Lloyd Wright Designs, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Frit and Feldspar Analysis Tables, 1968, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Geometry, 1953, 1982, undated, Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Glazes, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 30-31)
  - Indian Art, 1982, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Islamic Art, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Japan, 1954, 1968, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Korean Art, 1988, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Masonry, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Metal Techniques, 1968, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Molecular Aspects of Ceramic Materials, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 38)